<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tyler Krupicka]]></title>
  <link href="http://tylerkrupicka.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tylerkrupicka.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-24T23:29:13-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tylerkrupicka.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tyler Krupicka]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[tyler.krupicka13@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Started: About This Site]]></title>
    <link href="http://tylerkrupicka.github.io/blog/2014/06/21/getting-started-about-this-site/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-21T12:48:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tylerkrupicka.github.io/blog/2014/06/21/getting-started-about-this-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The last few weeks I&#8217;ve been working on developing this website as a place to post projects and thoughts as well as get more experience with web development. It&#8217;s finally at a point where I&#8217;m content with the styling and layout (for the moment) so I thought it would be good to post some of what I&#8217;ve learned so far.</p>


<!-- more -->


<p>When I originally planned on developing a site a year ago, I was daunted with the task of creating one from scratch. I didn&#8217;t want to use a pre-built platform, because you lose a lot of control of the site and can&#8217;t learn anything from it. This site is generated by <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>, a static site generator that adds features to <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>. Websites built using Octopress/Jekyll are generated locally, meaning that the site is assembled each time a change is made. This avoids the problem of having to work with databases and allows me to have full control over the appearance of the site.</p>


<p>Another bonus to having a static site is the ability to use git for version control and Github Pages for free hosting. Each time I want to update the site, I commit the most recent changes to the site&#8217;s repository on Github and the site is hosted from there. This system makes it really easy to maintain the site and keeps the cost of running it down. Additionally, I can still use my own domain name when accessing the site.</p>


<p>In summary, Octopress makes creating a static site really simple, while holding on to the customization that I want. Nice!</p>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
